# Andrew Rodman lead developer, system architect

206.355.7484 arodman@gmail.com

I am a vision led project manager who excels at taking customer requirements and turning them into easy to use deliverables. I have experience in the full stack of windows based software-as-a-service world, including but not limited to: database management and design, web-service design, user-interface design, system deployment, IIS configuration and management, domain configuration, email systems, automated reporting systems, security reviews, system documentation, and more. My passion is to deliver front-end experiences that exceed customer and industry expectations.

#### skills

## **Project Oversight**

Years of experience working with small teams to successfully quickly and effectively accomplish big tasks.

### Web Development

Solid understanding of hurdles and solutions at each level in software-as-a-service development, from database to front-end.

## Requirement Gathering

Proven history of working with multiple stake holders to define system requirements, supervise development, and deliver products.

#### techinical

C#/.NET	HTML/CSS	Javascript
JQuery	CVS - SVN/GIT	RESTful Services
SQL Design	M2M Design	SPA Design

#### experience

#### VendNovation

2005-Present

## System Architect, Project Manager, Developer

Joined the company in its infancy and grew with it, overseeing front-end interface design, database design, project definition, system architecture, system migrations, PCI certification, and much more.

## Seattle Pacific University

2001-2005

#### Information Technology Services

Provided technical support and training for students and staff on a variety of platforms. Assisted professors in preparation of class materials including audio recording and editing of online lectures. Provided image clean-up services for academic publishing.

## Logos Research Systems

1998-2001

#### Electronic Text Developer

Responsible for maintaining on-site archives. Scanned and converted documents to custom text formats using custom perl scripts. Proofread documents to ensure conversion accuracy.

#### projects

#### Windows Services

C#, Windows Server

Develope and maintain scalable automated delivery systems for reporting, real-time alert routing, and system health monitoring.

#### Mobile Interfaces

C#, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery

Built custom, touch based mobile inventory management interfaces including unique controls for value adjustments to maximize customer productivity.

#### Database Design

SQL Server, C#

Co-designed database structures for multiple real-time transaction based machine-to-machine inventory tracking and access control systems. Implemented SQL to C# object generator that provided data validation and CRUD actions based on SQL schemas

## User Interface Design

HTML, CSS, Javascript, C#

Responsible for look and feel as well as usability of several customer facing as well as internal platforms. Co-developed custom controls for quickly selecting hierarchical data sets. Developed custom JavaScript UI framework for supporting in house script service frontends.

## Migration to Cloud Services

AWS, Server 2012, SQL Server

Oversaw migration from bare-metal to cloud based hosting on AWS including SQL Server data migration and deployment of IIS hosted websites.

## **System Integrations**

C#, SOAP, REST, Ruby

Designed and implemented multiple specialized third-party integrations, working with remote teams to define system operations and test implementations.

## Office Systems Support

Microsoft Server, Cisco Device

Maintain office network security by configuring Cisco Firewall rules, maintaining domain configurations, managing user accounts and security settings, etc.

education

## Seattle Pacific University

2001-2005

**BS** Computer Science